Contact

tonnyed@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tonyosaigbovo-edos-141408106 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Linux

Ansible

Docker Products

Languages

English

Certifications

Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist

Zerto Certified Profesional

Dell EMC Server Credential 2018

Tony Osaigbovo Edos

Software Engineer & Linux Dev-op Engineer at MAXIMUS UK

Manchester, Greater Manchester, United Kingdom

Summary

I am a diligent highly motivated Senior Lead Linux Devops Engineer and Developer with proven record of relating with customer and have Successfully delivered exceptional services at the highest level, I am highly organized. My Education and professional experience to date has provided a wealth of specialist skills and expertise but I am open to learn and I am determined to take on challenges and to pursuing my future career goals.

Experience

MAXIMUS UK
Software Engineer & Linux Dev-op Engineer
January 2019 - Present
United Kingdom

Dev-Ops:

Experience:

- . Maintained Git work-flows for version control (source Code Management)
- . Developed and maintained automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment using jenkins
- . provisioned Servers and deployed feature using Ansible.
- . Built and deployed containers for implementing Micro-service Architecture using docker and Lxc.
- . orchestrated Containers cluster using Docker Swarm / Kubernetes

Used Tools:

automation:

- Ansible
- Terraform

Deployment:

- Git Lab-runner with shell executor with Ansible-playbooks
- Jenkins

Version-Control:

- Git Lab Ci

Regular Tasks:

- . building development infrastructure environment for testing, staging and live
- . database management.
- back-up
- -load-balancing
- . designing the full ci and cd pipeline
- . building and implement ci-cd life-cycle
- . designing and automating code-deployment from testing to stating to live environment
- . creating wiki to document the entire process

Development:

- creating modules as required by project manager statement

Concept and design:

- MVC
- MVVM (knockout.js)
- CRUD
- Service and Api-Endpoint Concept
- php
- javascript

@RubyPartime Freelance Software Developer2015 - Present

Manchester, United Kingdom

Developing Web apps Using ruby on ruby on rails framework mostly hosted using heroku with github repousing post-gressql dbusing mvc architecture pattern-

iomart

1 year 1 month

Linux System Administrator/ infrastructure Engineer July 2018 - January 2019 (7 months) Manchester, United Kingdom

Data Center Linux System Engineer January 2018 - July 2018 (7 months) Manchester, United Kingdom

LINUX Server Deployment and Support

Deploy, Configure and Manage Systems: Network and Service Configuration Deploy, Configure and Manage Systems: Network and Service Configuration, Maintain Systems: Configure Yum Repository and Update Linux Kernel Maintain Systems: Configure Yum Repository and Update Linux Kernel, Manage Users and Groups: Managing Local User AccountsManage Users and Groups: Managing Local User Accounts,

Configure Local Storage: Linux Filesystems and PartitionsConfigure Local Storage: Linux Filesystems and Partitions,

Remote access configuration [e.g. ftp, ssh, scp], NGINX and Apache configuration & debugging,

Mail server configuration [or sendmail/postfix], Database server configuration [or MySQL/MariaDB],

Red Hat clustering, CageFS + LVE, Caching - Varnish, APC, Memcached

Network Configuration and Support

Access Lists, VPN/Debugging, VLANs and VTP Firewall deployment (pfsense & ASA)

Basic Network Troubleshooting

Cloud Virtualization Management and Support
Creating/Configuring VMs, Creating/configuring networks (DVSwtiches/port
groups)

XEN Platform Management, Vmware Esxi, Vcenter and Hyper V Platform Management

Aws EC2 Platform Management, Aws EC3 Platform Management.

NHS

System Engineer - Contractor October 2017 - January 2018 (4 months)

United Kingdom

Autocab

System Engineer
June 2016 - October 2017 (1 year 5 months)

Manchester, United Kingdom

Analyzed software design and provided technical input, as well as, application demonstration, interface control documentation, and personnel training.

Provided Linux CentOS system administration configuring and kickstart;

To install and configure new software applications To resolve incidents and upgrade different types of software and hardware.

Telephony -PBX – Diagnosing, configuring and optimizing all VoIP/IP-PBX telephone systems and services;

Phone Apps – fixing any application incident that is disrupting the application service for End users and finding bugs and report bugs, also integrating payment service. Example judo pay and sage pay.

TalkTalk Business
System Engineer
January 2016 - June 2016 (6 months)
Lancashire

Manchester Metropolitan University System Engineer May 2015 - December 2015 (8 months)

Page 4 of 6

- -Diagnose and resolve software, hardware, Networking infrastructure issue
- -Design and implement Configuration Manager 2012 R2 and creating application packages where appropriate to allow customised silent installs to be available in the application portal.
- -Created tasks and collections as well as updated/performed troubleshooting of distribution point issues for package deployments
- -Troubleshooting PC, Laptops and Mobile Devices
- -Proving 2nd Line Support for Users
- -Installing and Configuration of Telecommunication equipment like Cisco phone using call manager
- -Logging of IT related incident from phone or mail via a Help Desk Software
- -To take ownership of issues by carrying out problem analysis to implement temporary or permanent fixes with the aim of restoring service to the customer as soon as possible; escalating incidents to other support teams where necessary.
- -Accurately record & Logging, update and document requests using the IT service desk system.
- -Install and configure new IT equipment.
- -resolving incidents and upgrade different types of software like Office apps like outlook, endnote, OneNote
- -Maintain a first class level of customer service ensuring that all customers are treated efficiently and in accordance with SLA
- -Responsible for supporting: Windows XP/Vista/Windows 7/ Office 2003 and 2007, Windows Server 2008/2012, Active Directory management Exchange /2008/2012, Blackberry Server/Windows Mobile, Backup products, Anti-Virus products, DNS/DHCP, TCP/IP, Ethernet, wireless router and Firewall Configurations.
- -Resolving printer related issues like paper jam, Fuser related problem, drum replacement, Replacing maintenance kit, tonner / Cartridge, and using Safecom to monitor printers.

Bamis Tech Solutions
System Engineer
December 2012 - May 2015 (2 years 6 months)
Bolton, United Kingdom

- Deployment devices such as Computers, laptops, Desktops etc.
- Hardware and operating system installation
- Installation and deployment of applications
- Laptop and PC build
- Software and hardware installation/support/ compatibility testing

- Microsoft Server installation, Deployment of Microsoft Active directory directory services ,DNS, DHCP
- · Wiping of XP machine hard drive
- Mapping of Network tool and Peripherals like printer
- Managed print Deployment of new printing solution
- Data backup and recovery
- · Website design and maintenance
- Configuration and troubleshooting of hardware issues
- Computer maintenance and repair
- Detect, diagnose and resolve most PC, printer and peripheral device faults

LimeLight Services

System Engineer

July 2011 - November 2012 (1 year 5 months)

- Diagnostics and correction of network connectivity problems
- Hardware installations e.g. physical memory, graphics card, CPU etc.
- Computer and laptop repairs with CompTIA Six step methodology
- · Configuration and troubleshooting hardware
- Window server Active Directory services, DNS, DHCP Deployment.
- Network cable installation and Mapping of peripherals,
- Fault diagnosing and removing of errors from computers & Network work
- Configure and maintains PCs & IT systems
- Detect, diagnose and resolve most PC, printer and peripheral device faults
- Software and hardware installation & support

Education

The University of Bolton

Bachelor of Science (BSc) (Top Up), Computing Technology · (2010 - 2011)

NIIT

Higher National Diploma (HND), Network Engineer (2007 - 2010)

Viena College

Computer Installation and Repair Technology/Technician · (2005 - 2007)